<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-23T17:16:33-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">~$hawn_Zhang is:</title><subtitle>Welcome to Shawn&apos;s website! Excuse the mess around here as we work on cleaning this place up!</subtitle><author><name>~$hawn_Zhang is:</name></author><entry><title type="html">Testing collections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/collections-test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing collections" /><published>2023-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/collections-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/collections-test/">&lt;p&gt;This is an excerpt for a personal post.
Testing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;–excerpt–&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing the personal collection&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>~$hawn_Zhang is:</name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">This is an excerpt for a personal post. Testing…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SANS Holiday Hack Challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/sans-holiday-hack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SANS Holiday Hack Challenge" /><published>2023-01-05T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/sans-holiday-hack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/sans-holiday-hack/"></content><author><name>~$hawn_Zhang is:</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="professional" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“You and Your Research” by Richard Hamming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/you-and-your-research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“You and Your Research” by Richard Hamming" /><published>2023-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/you-and-your-research</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/you-and-your-research/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/a1zDuOPkMSw?si=MIUeGof8ki9bOfHL&quot;&gt;Hamming, “You and Your Research” (June 6, 1995)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon this lecture by Richard Hamming, one of the early pioneers in computer science.  Hamming is well-known for developing error correction methods used in computer networks, but in this lecture titled “You and Your Research,” Hamming speaks more broadly on the topics of science and how success is achieved in any academic field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many insightful moments throughout the lecture, so it’s well worth the watch.  But here I will summarize of the points made by Hamming that really stood out to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed very clearly at Bell Laboratories, those who work with the door shut may be working just as hard ten years later but they don’t know what to work on.  They are not connected to reality.  Those who had the door open may very well know what’s important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier on in the lecture Hamming dismisses the misconception that luck and intelligence are the defining factors that lead to success, and here he makes the brilliant point that it doesn’t matter how smart you are if you are always working on the wrong problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The guys with the door closed were often very well able, very gifted but they seemed to work always on slightly the wrong problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>~$hawn_Zhang is:</name></author><category term="opinions" /><summary type="html">Hamming, “You and Your Research” (June 6, 1995) I recently stumbled upon this lecture by Richard Hamming, one of the early pioneers in computer science. Hamming is well-known for developing error correction methods used in computer networks, but in this lecture titled “You and Your Research,” Hamming speaks more broadly on the topics of science and how success is achieved in any academic field. There are many insightful moments throughout the lecture, so it’s well worth the watch. But here I will summarize of the points made by Hamming that really stood out to me. I’ve noticed very clearly at Bell Laboratories, those who work with the door shut may be working just as hard ten years later but they don’t know what to work on. They are not connected to reality. Those who had the door open may very well know what’s important. Earlier on in the lecture Hamming dismisses the misconception that luck and intelligence are the defining factors that lead to success, and here he makes the brilliant point that it doesn’t matter how smart you are if you are always working on the wrong problem. The guys with the door closed were often very well able, very gifted but they seemed to work always on slightly the wrong problem.</summary></entry></feed>